你好 我是迈克
Hi, I'm Mike.
我叫穆斯塔法
And I'm Mustafa.
我们在MetaFair从事触感感知的研究
And we're working on touch perception at MetaFair.
MetaFair团队兴奋地推出
Our MetaFair team is excited to release
几项机器人技术的最新成果
several cutting-edge developments in robotics
以及触觉感知 这标志着
and touch perception that mark a significant step
我们对物理世界理解的重大飞跃
forward in our understanding of the physical world
以及我们与之进行有意义互动的能力
and our ability to interact with it in meaningful ways.
我们来谈谈SPARSH
Let's begin with SPARSH.
SPARSH是首个通用触觉表示系统
SPARSH is the first general-purpose touch representation
适用于各种触觉传感器
that works across any tactile sensor
和任务
and any task.
为了实现这个目标 我们使用460,000张触觉图像
To achieve this, we train SPARSH using 460,000 tactile images
通过自我监督学习来训练SPARSH
with self-supervised learning.
在基准测试中 SPARSH的表现优于
In benchmarks, we find that SPARSH outperforms
特定任务和传感器的模型
task and sensor-specific models
平均超过95%
by an average of over 95%.
SPARSH提供了预训练基础模型
SPARSH unlocks pre-trained backbones
使我们测量力量
that allow us to measure properties like forces
和接触特性
and contact
这些特性是视觉无法察觉的
which are imperceptible through vision.
我们的目标是激励社区来构建
Our aim is to empower the community to build
并将这些模型扩展到新的应用领域
and scale these models towards novel applications.
接下来我们将介绍Digit360
Which leads us to Digit360
一种突破性触觉传感器 具有人类水平的
a breakthrough tactile sensor that perceives the world with human-level
触觉感知能力
touch sensing capabilities.
搭载设备内的人工智能
With on-device AI
Digit360 在本地处理信息 做出决策
Digit360 processes information locally and makes decisions
灵感来自人类和动物的反射机制
inspired by the reflex function in people and animals.
这使得传感器能够迅速响应各种输入
This allows a sensor to respond quickly to various inputs,
例如针刺的接触
such as the poke of a needle
或是网球的变形
or the flex of a tennis ball.
它能迅速响应各种输入
It responds quickly to various inputs,
模拟人类手指的动作
mimicking the performance of a human finger
因此 它成为了多种应用的创新方案
making it an innovative solution for multiple applications.
我们把Digit360和DigitPlexus结合在一起了
We've also paired Digit360 with DigitPlexus
一个用于标准化机器人传感器连接和交互的平台
a platform that standardizes robotic sensor connection and interactions,
模拟人手在具身人工智能中的触觉信息处理
mimicking the human hand's touch information processing for embodied AI.
DigitPlexus提供硬件和软件组件
DigitPlexus provides hardware and software components
便于轻松集成触觉传感技术到机器人系统
for easy integration of touch sensing technology into robotic systems.
最后 我们和GelSight、Wannick Robotics合作了
Finally, we are partnering with GelSight and Wannick Robotics
他们是行业领军者
who are leaders in the industry,
致力于开发和推广这些触觉传感技术
to develop and commercialize these touch sensing innovations.
我们希望让社区一起参与
Our hope is to bring the community along
共同推动人工智能和机器人领域的进步
and work together in driving the progress in AI and robotics.
在机器人领域之外 这些进展可以帮助我们将物理世界
Beyond robotics, these advancements can help bring the physical world
与数字世界更紧密地连接
and the digital world closer together.
想象一下在游戏里拿起一个物品
Imagine picking up an object in a game
或是在网上购物时扫描一块布
or scanning a piece of fabric during online shopping.
这甚至可能推动假肢技术的发展
This could even lead to advancements in prosthetics.
我们希望建立一个充满活力的社区
Our hope is to build a driving community
并最终让触觉感应技术在现实生活中变得切实可行
and ultimately make touch sensing practical out there in the real world.
这项研究让我们更接近于
This work brings us one step closer
理解触觉数字化的真正含义
to understanding what it means to digitize touch.
那个未来几乎就在眼前了
And that future is almost within reach.